ANIRUDH MENON

Mumbai | +91-9687933490 | menonanirudh@outlook.com

To Whomsoever It Concerns

Dear Recipient

Over the last 18 years in my professional endeavour, I have had the experience of working in the domain of enterprise sales, business development, pre-sales, operations, and customer service.

As an enterprise sales professional, I have been able to contribute significantly in terms of revenue and new logos for the organizations that I have represented. If I take the case of last 5 years, during the pandemic period in particular, I was able to close INR 1.5 Cr worth annual recurring revenue in new business.

Having worked in both India and international market over these years, I do carry the sales and business acumen of engaging with clients, negotiating with them, and signing them up. With this background, I am looking forward to being associated with your organization in case there is a suitable opportunity that fits my profile.

There has been a disparity in the role that was assigned to me and the work that is assigned to me under that role. Due to this disparity, I am looking for a change. My previous company got acquired by a larger set up and hence, I had to move out. Hence you will notice a short duration in my previous assignment in Bangalore.

Look forward to your response

Sincerely,

Anirudh Menon

ANIRUDH MENON

Mumbai | +91-9687933490 | menonanirudh@outlook.com

ABOUT ME

Sales professional with 18 years of experience in the field of sales, business development, marketing, operations & customer service. Have been a part of the legal-tech domain for last 6 years, catering to Indian subcontinent and North America.

EDUCATION

MBA/ 2004

Specialization – Marketing **Sardar Patel University**

B.Sc/ 2002

Specialization - Instrumentation **Sardar Patel University**

EXPERTISE

- Pipeline Management
- Sales Operations
- Commercial Negotiation
- Contract Negotiation
- Coaching & mentoring

EXPERIENCE

Wheebox

Functional Leader Enterprise Business / March 2022 - Present

Responsible for managing revenue in the enterprise division with special focus on BFSI segment

Ultria

Senior Manager Digital Sales / September 2021 – March 2022

- Heading the mid-enterprise sales division.
- Managing a team of Digital Sales Managers
- Individual contributor in the sales pipeline

The company got acquired by another entity in March 2022 so there was a major rejig in the mid-management positions

PracticeLeague

Manager Corporate Sales / July 2019 – August 2021

- Heading the India Sales Team
- Hunting new opportunities & conduct discoveries
- Engage in commercial & contractual negotiations
- Drive revenue for the organization
- Oversee the performance of sales team

PracticeLeague

Asst. Manager Corporate Sales / September 2016 – June 2019

- Responsible for hunting new deals
- Part of a sales team that drives revenue
- Give product demonstrations to prospective clients

Note

Prior to PracticeLeague, I worked in international business for **12 years** where I was driving **new customer acquisition, account management and project transition** for enterprise sales.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Closed INR 1.5 Cr in the F.Y 2020-21 (during lockdown) in new business
- Created a pipeline of USD 500,000 in 6 months from Sept 2021 till date
- Helped team member close two accounts from September 2021 till date.
 Cumulative value \$105,000 (ARR)
- Signed up clients like Bajaj Finance, TVS Motors, TVS Tyres EPIC Group (Hong Kong) and many more between 2019 and 2020
- In the year 2008-2009 closed 5 accounts in mobile app development with an average ticket size of \$7500 per opportunity
- Generated 15 new logos during the lockdown period in enterprise business